

Kuba Kuźma

Senior Ruby, JavaScript Developer

Full stack developer with more than 15+ years of experience in building web applications. Involved in all stages of the software development life cycle. Passionate about learning new technologies and sharing knowledge.

♠ kubakuzma.com kuba@kubakuzma.com pithub.com/qoobaa in linkedin.com/in/qoobaa

SKILLS

Ruby on Rails React JavaScript PostgreSQL Node.js Git GNU/Linux Emacs Database Design

API Design DevOps Docker Kubernetes AWS GCP

EXPERIENCE

Senior Full Stack Developer

Triage Inc., Ottawa, Canada (remotely)

October 2018 — current

- developed a data exploration and analysis tool to efficiently manage over 2 TB of Al training data
- streamlined storage and processing of 2M images by migrating to ActiveStorage
- redesigned <u>API</u> to align with a wizard-like <u>UI</u> for 200K customers, simplifying the interface and reducing endpoint count
- rapidly built a skin condition classification tool for 20 dermatologists and a team of <u>GPs</u>, leveraging *Metabase* for accelerated delivery
- optimized staging and production environments seamlessly migrating them out of Kubernetes clusters, deployed with Kamal, resulted in threefold cost reduction

Senior Full Stack Developer

Freeletics GmbH, Munich, Germany (remotely)

July 2014 — September 2018

- migrated legacy PHP-based infrastructure to Ruby on Rails, streamlining the tech stack and improving maintainability
- optimized the build process for an *Angular* application, reducing build time tenfold and significantly accelerating development
- designed and implemented a token-based authentication mechanism, introducing access tokens that enabled the extraction of the authentication service and modularization of the *Rails* application
- broke down a monolithic *Rails* application into multiple services (<u>APIs</u>), allowing for separate release cycles for distinct applications (Freeletics Fitness, Freeletics Nutrition, etc.)

Senior Full Stack Developer

Quickjack Solutions Inc., Ottawa, Canada (remotely)

October 2012 — June 2014

- <u>Canadian Health Registry Database</u> developed a *Ruby on Rails* and *Angular*-based platform that processed nearly \$2M in fees for the client since inception.
- bilingual spatial data visualization tool for <u>Search and Rescue Canada</u> built a single-page application using *Ember*, *Leaflet*, *D3*, and *Crossfilter*, designed to launch from *Microsoft SharePoint* on *Internet Explorer*, enabled in-browser visualization and filtering of 100MB+ *ArcGIS* datasets without server-side code

Senior Full Stack Developer

Tiramizoo GmbH, Munich, Germany (remotely)

October 2011 — September 2012

- designed and developed a highly modular <u>API</u> using *Node.js*, deploying it into production, later rewritten to *Ruby on Rails*
- implemented an abstraction layer to enable switching from Google Directions <u>API</u> to alternative providers, resulting in substantial cost savings for the company

JavaScript Developer

Strobe Inc., San Francisco, USA (remotely)

June 2011 — September 2011

- collaborated with a remarkable team, including Yehuda Katz, Carl Lerche, José Valim, Peter Wagenet, Piotr Sarnacki, and others
- developed a social add-on for the Strobe platform that simplified integration with Twitter and Facebook <u>APIs</u>, enhancing the platform's functionality and user experience

Ruby on Rails Developer

Object Reload, Gliwice, Poland

August 2008 — June 2011

• various commercial projects using Ruby on Rails (details available upon request)

EDUCATION

MSc in Computer Science

Silesian University of Technology, Gliwice, Poland

2004-2009

LANGUAGES

- Polish (native)
- English (fluent)
- Spanish (basic)
- German (beginner)